MAURICIO GONZÁLEZ

Mercedes Norte, Heredia | (H) 22626412 | (C) 87075176 | gonzalez.araya.mauricio@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Driven professional with broad technical skill-set, very strong attention to detail, and over 10 years experience in front-end and back-end web development. Able to multitask and juggle multiple pressing projects simultaneously. On top of the latest trends and technologies. Ability to improvise, troubleshoot, take ownership, and learn new skills on the job.

SKILLS

- PHP
- Ruby
- C#
- Python
- Javascript
- HTML
- CSS
- SQL

- Laravel, Yii, Wordpress, Drupal
- Rails, Spree
- · ReactJS, JQuery, NodeJS
- Bootstrap, Susy
- MySQL, MS SQL Server, PostgreSQL
- Vim, Sublime, Atom
- Grunt, Bower, Gulp

WORK HISTORY

DECEMBER 2014-CURRENT

- Developer | OfficeSpaceSoftware | Santa Ana, Costa Rica • Frontend and backend development for the product.
 - Technologies used: Compass, ReactJs, Ruby on Rails, MariaDB.

OCTOBER 2013-NOVEMBER 2014

Web Developer | BlueFountainMedia | New York, USA

- I was part of a medium sized distributed team of developers(USA, Argentina, Portugal and Costa Rica).
- Developed frontend and backend work with: Wordpress, Magento, Drupal and a propietary CMS based on Yii.
- Sole developer for BaldorFood: http://www.baldorfood.com/

SEPTEMBER 2013-NOVEMBER 2013

Web Developer | Edify Software Consulting | Alajuela, Costa Rica

Developed mainly prototypes for clients such as Kaplan and Macmillan using CanJS and

some AngularJS.

OCTOBER 2008-SEPTEMBER 2013

Developer - Sr. Web Developer - Technology Lead | The Hangar / Critical Mass LATAM | Heredia, Costa Rica

- Filled a variety of development roles, both in leadership and non-leadership positions.
- Assisted with the managing of a team of 20+.
- Direct contact with clients. Providing technical project estimation.
- Interviewing.
- Project oversight.
- Developing of web applications with both frontend technologies and backend languages.
- Some of the projects I was able to work on include:
- Clorox: BritaWatermark mobile application(PhoneGap, SASS, Laravel)
- Infiniti: Infiniti USA (Groovy on Grails)
- Adidas: miAdidas, Adidas.com (Frontend)
- Mattel: Maxsteel.com (DotNet MVC4)
- ATT: EDO (Frontend)
- BestBuy (Drupal 7).

JANUARY 2002-AUGUST 2008

Web/DB Developer ICCS | Costa Rica / Panama

- Design new custom sites and applications for customers.
- Built a real time online reporting(C# and SQL Server).
- Assisted the DBA with his duties.
- Part of the team that wrote a distributed poker application(C#).

EDUCATION

0045

2015

Bachelor of Science: Systems Engineering Universidad Nacional, Heredia, Costa Rica Heredia, Costa Rica

INTERESTS

Literature, all things sci-fi, robotics and tennis

Literature, all trilligs sci-ii, robotics and termis

LANGUAGES

Spanish (Native), English (Advanced), German (Beginner)